Raymond Flores

Phone: (956) 789-3046 • E-Mail: raymondfflores@gmail.com

I am a Senior Full Stack Engineer with 5+ years experience with tools such as Node.js, Express, Angular, React, PostgreSQL, etc. I have mentored and code reviewed junior developers on JavaScript, HTML, CSS & Web Application Development, created and integrated RESTful API endpoints, and developed web/mobile clients.

Skills

Programming Languages – JavaScript, C++, Python, PHP, Bash, C#

Markup & Formats - HTML, CSS, JSON, XML, HTML5, CSS3, Sass, EJS, Jade

Database Systems - PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB, Redis, SQL Server

Libraries & Frameworks - Node. js, Express, React, Redux, Material UI, Webpack, AngularJS, Socket.io, Angular, jQuery, Bootstrap, Gulp, Require.js, Ionic, Cordova, PhoneGap, Knex, BookShelf.js, ES6, TypeScript, Nginx, Nightwatch.js, Mocha, Selenium

Version Control - Git, SVN

Experience

Ticketmaster Jan 2019 – Present

Senior Software Engineer I – Pharr, TX

- Built a React app that in turn replaced the legacy front end because of its optimization, load speeds and code
- Automated tedious tasks by building simple intuitive forms that improved efficiency and eliminated data input errors
- Automated and digitalized business flows that were previously done on paper. This is turned saved company tremendous amount in time and costs for paper.

Justuno Apr 2018 - Jan 2019 justuno.com

Senior Back End Engineer - Austin, TX

- Responsible for app store integrations to Shopify, Bigcommerce, and Cloudflare, which allowed for having Justuno more accessible and being a one click install for e-commerce stores on these platforms. Resulted in an increase of daily downloads.
- Developed push notifications as a service using Node/Express and built a user dashboard (React) that allowed Justuno clients to send customized push notifications to their customers who opted in.
- Automated testing and unit testing using Selenium, NightWatch, Mocha, and Chai
- Developed an Oauth 2.0 Server for 3rd party applications to authenticate with Justuno
- Wrote scripts to update/fix hundreds of thousands of data points
- ES6, Promises, Async/Await
- Used React Components, React Router, Webpack, and Redux to build front end

PokerSports

Oct 2016 - Apr 2018

Full Stack Engineer – Austin, TX

pokersports.com

- Responsible for all content on the PokerSports website, Real-Time Fantasy Sports Multiplayer Card Game (FantasyStud Web App), and FantasyStud Mobile App
- Integrating 3rd party services with our products like PayPal Merchant API for deposits and withdrawals, SendGrid API for emails and mass emails, FantasyData for real-time sports stats.
- Building and setting up servers using CentOS, Ubuntu, Bash, NGINX, Apache2, and PM2.

- Automating builds and other tasks using GULP and Cron jobs to run timely scripts in NodeJS or Bash.
- Managing a team of 2 Junior Developers. Delegated tasks to them and code reviewed their work.
- Automated browser testing & unit testing using NightWatchJS, Selenium, and Mocha.
- Front-end development using AngularJS, Back-end development using Node.js, and other tools including Ionic, PostgreSQL, Gulp, and Require.js, Redis, Socket.io.
- Built a very complex web app which architecture very closely relates to an online poker game. Created peer-to-peer/peer-to-host connections so that users could easily communicate with each other and the server with minimal latency. Completed research and development of online multiplayer architecture for host to client multiplayer games. Successfully orchestrated the most complex task of making sure all clients were in sync with each other based on server clock (precisely calculated client to server latency and code runtime on client side so that timers never ran out of sync with server).

Bloxmob Inc.

Feb 2016 - Apr 2017

Full Stack Engineer - Austin, TX

bloxmob.com

- Developed a platform that lets users create mobile apps without knowing how to code.
- Continuously built and integrated new features. Conducted code reviews and maintained and optimized current infrastructure. End-to-End (E2E) testing solutions.
- Front-end development using AngularJS, Back-end development using Node.js, and other tools including Ionic, PostgreSQL, Gulp, and Require.js.
- Built analytics for business intelligence and market outreach.

Think Tech Labs

Aug 2015 - Jan 2016

Software Developer I – Austin, TX

rethinkcrm.com

- Developed software solutions for real estate agents on Salesforce Platform.
- Collaborated with business analysts, product managers, and other engineers to incorporate functionality into residential product.
- Front-end development using JavaScript, HTML, CSS, VisualForce pages, and Lightning Components. Also maintained existing tools and infrastructure as necessary. Conducted unit tests for server side code. Documented software functionality. Worked on a 4-8 member team to continuously build and integrate new features.

Perficientur

Jan 2015 - Aug 2015

Node.js Full Stack Developer – McAllen, TX

perficientur.net

- Developed custom business software for clients that provided automated workflows, valuable data, business intelligence, key performance indicators, and automated alerts in real time.
- Rapid prototyping for client feedback, developed and used RESTful APIs, agile based projects, data-driven applications.
- Developed and maintained web application systems using Node.js, AngularJS, Express, PostgreSQL and Amazon Web Services (AWS). Used AngularJS for Single Page Application development.
- Managed a team of 3-4 programmers and designed solutions for our projects.

JPT Consulting & Services

Jan 2014 - Dec 2014

Node.js Full Stack Developer – McAllen, TX

ipt-la.com

- Collaborated with a team of software engineers and hardware engineers to develop a resource monitoring system (Safe Wireless Remote Sensor) for oil, gas, & water. Main development tools used were Node.js, AngularJS, Express, PostgreSQL, and Redis.
- Rapid prototyping for client feedback, developed and used RESTful APIs, agile based projects, data-driven applications and Amazon Web Services (AWS).
- Worked on many other local projects to acquire revenue for research & development of SafeWireless Remote Sensor. These projects were mainly for local businesses to help optimize and digitize their business process or

cognitive model of a process. Also provided analytics to help provide information for better business decision-making.

Education

The University of Texas - Pan American

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science

Aug 2011- Aug 2015

GPA: 3.42 (3.8 in Computer Science Related Courses)

Online Courses

- Object Oriented Programming in JavaScript
- Designing RESTful APIs
- Full Stack Development
- Programming in React
- JavaScript Design Patterns
- JavaScript Testing